TRAVIS NELSON

SOFTWARE CRAFTSMAN / FULL-STACK DEVELOPER

PROFESSIONAL STATEMENT

12+ years experience in server and client-side development. Certified ScrumMaster, Certified Umbraco Level I and Level II Developer, Stanford University Software Security Foundations certificate, involvement in Intellectual Property Steering Committee contributing to several patent filings and awards, Innovator of the Quarter award, complete web application development from proposal through project delivery, maintenance and marketing, and work with distinguished clients including EA Games, Terminix, TruGreen, and Sage Software. Experience with Microsoft Azure, Amazon AWS, and Rackspace Cloud.

SOCIAL

stackoverflow.travis.io

witter.travis.io

in linkedin.travis.io

github.travis.io

CONTACT

Address

280 Jeanette St. Canton, GA 30114

Email

me@travis.io

Mobile/SMS

941-276-0763

Skype

trnelson

EXPERIENCE

2009 - Present

Scientific Games (formerly Williams Interactive, WMS Gaming)

Principal Software Engineer II

Server and client-side development. Authentication mechanisms, website architecture, internal and third-party APIs, CMS integration using Umbraco (legacy projects). Also involved in build and automation processes, source code administration (GitHub Enterprise, Visual SVN), Agile, and orchestration of process improvements within the organization.

2014 - Present

ThreadKM

Senior Development Consultant

Consulting as core team member for legal technology startup ThreadKM. Responsible for product UI, user experience, and major feature development, both server and client side. Product development with HTML/CSS, Bootstrap, jQuery, Ruby, Angular, js, Redis. Hosted using Amazon EC2 and Digital Ocean using Ubuntu Server, Nginx, Unicorn.

2007-2009

Marketing Max

Creative Director and Lead Developer

Design and development for clients including Terminix, TruGreen, Sage Software, and ComputerJobs.com. Managed projects from consultation through design, launch, maintenance, and marketing. Development in ASP.NET using C# and SQL Server, and use of third-party APIs and tools such as Google Maps, Authorize.Net, and PayPal.

2006-2007

Selina Naturally (formerly The Grain & Salt Society)

Website / Systems Administrator

Responsible for management and maintenance of information systems including computers, data network, servers, phone network, and website. Development of website features. Design and programming support for marketing team, including creation and launch of email campaigns, list management, and website promotions.

SKILLS

.NET (C#) HTML/CSS JavaScript .NET Web API SQL Server Git/SVN

	_	_

SOLID
Design Patterns
Agile
Jenkins
Graphic Design
Marketing



TRAVIS NELSON

SOFTWARE CRAFTSMAN / FULL-STACK DEVELOPER

PERSONAL INTERESTS

Graphic Design
Branding
Writing
Marketing
Business
Lifelong Learning
Passive Income
Photography
Strength Training

CONTACT

Address

280 Jeanette St. Canton, GA 30114

Email

me@travis.io

Mobile/SMS

941-276-0763

Skype

trnelson

EDUCATION

Ongoing Computer Science

Kennesaw State University, Kennesaw, GA

4.0 GPA, courses include: Statistics, Algebra, Calculus, Macroeconomics,

Microeconomics, English Composition II – Technical Writing, Psychology, Ethics, Speech Communications - Public Speaking.

1999 - 2002 Advanced Diploma - Multimedia Production

Confederation College of Applied Arts and Technology, Thunder Bay, ON

3.74 GPA, Dean's List graduate of the three-year Multimedia Production program at Confederation College, including successful completion of a four month, 576-hour internship.

INTERESTS AND AREAS OF STUDY

SOLID design, design patterns, test-driven design and mocking, continuous integration, Agile and Kanban, cloud development (Microsoft Azure, Amazon AWS, Rackspace Cloud, Parse.com), software architecture (services-oriented architecture, microservices, domain-driven design, caching, table/blob/queue), mobile, single page applications (Angular,js), UI design (Bootstrap, jQuery, LESS, SASS), analytics, marketing, user experience, security, API design, best practices.